本课程的主要目标是
Our primary goal in this course is
学习如何制作
to learn how to produce software that
是安全的，容易理解，
is safe from bugs, easy to understand,
准备好改变。
and ready for change.
这是什么意思？
And what do we mean by that?
好吧，免受虫害意味着它的行为是正确的
Well, safe from bugs means that it behaves correctly
现在，但同时也是防御性的，
right now, but also that it's defensive,
它能防止将来可能出现的虫子。
that it guards against bugs that might crop up in the future.
容易理解意味着你
Easy to understand means that you're
能够与未来的程序员沟通
able to communicate to future programmers who
需要理解并修改代码，
need to understand and make changes to the code,
比如修复错误或者添加新功能。
like fixing bugs or adding new features.
未来的程序员可能就是你。
A future programmer might actually be you.
如果你不写的话你会很惊讶你会忘记
You'd be surprised how much you forget if you don't write it
对你未来的自己有多大的帮助
down and how much it helps your own future self to have
一个好的代码设计。
a good design in your code.
准备好改变意味着你的软件已经准备好了
And ready for change means that your software is ready
对于新功能，请更改其周围的环境。
for new features, changes in the environment around it.
软件总是变化的。
Software always changes.
有些设计使这些改变变得容易。
Some designs make it easy to make those changes.
另一些则需要扔掉并重写大量代码，
Others require throwing away and rewriting a lot of code,
这不好。
and that's not good.
现在软件还有其他重要的特性，
Now there are other important properties of software,
比如它的运行速度，可用性
like how fast it runs, how usable
对于最终用户来说，这是多么的安全。
it is for end users, how secure it is against attackers.
他们可能会和这三个人交换。
And they may trade off against these three.
但这是6005年我们关心的三大问题。
But these are the big three that we care about in 6005.
我们会一遍又一遍地讨论这些问题。
We'll come back to these over and over.
软件开发人员通常把这些放在首位
Software developers generally put these foremost
在构建软件的实践中。
in the practice of building software.
每种语言都值得思考
It's worth thinking about every language
特性，每一个编程实践，每一个设计
feature, every programming practice, and every design
模式，我们在这门课上学习的每一个想法
pattern, every idea that we study in this course
了解他们与三巨头的关系。
and understanding how they relate to the big three.
每次阅读结束后我们都会这么做。
And we'll do that at the end of every reading.
为什么这门课是用Java教的
Now why is this course taught in Java rather
而不是Python和JavaScript？
than Python and JavaScript?
一个原因是安全。
Well, one reason is safety.
Java有静态检查。
Java has static checking.
主要是静态类型检查
Primarily, it's static-type checking
但是还有其他类型的静态检查，
but there are other kinds of static checks,
同样，你的代码必须从
too, like your code has to return values from methods that
期望返回值。
are expected to return values.
因为我们在这门课上学习软件工程
Since we're studying software engineering in this course
安全性是这种方法的一个关键原则，
and safety from bugs is a key tenet of that approach,
Java拨号安全性高达11，因此
Java dials safety up to 11 so it makes
它是学习优秀软件工程的好语言
it a good language for learning about good software engineering
实践。
practices.
现在当然可以编写安全的代码了
Now it's certainly possible to write safe code
在Python这样的动态语言中，
in dynamic languages like Python,
但更容易理解
but it's easier to understand what
如果你先学会如何
you need to do if you first learn how
用一种安全的静态检查语言。
in a safe statically-checked language.
另一个原因是无处不在。
Another reason is ubiquity.
Java广泛应用于研究、教育和工业领域。
Java's widely used in research, education, and industry.
它运行在许多平台上，不仅仅是Windows、Mac和Linux。
It runs on many platforms, not just Windows, Mac, and Linux.
它可以用于网络编程，
It can be used for web programming,
在服务器和客户端
both in the server and the client
以及本地安卓程序。
and for native Android programming.
尽管其他编程语言更好
Although other programming languages are much better
适合于编程、Scheme和ML的教学
suited to teaching programming, Scheme and ML
是优秀教学语言的好例子，
are good examples of good teaching languages,
不幸的是，这些语言不是
unfortunately these languages are not
广泛存在于现实世界中。
widespread in the real world.
你简历上的Java将被识别
Java on your resume will be recognized
作为一种可销售的技能，Scheme和ML不会。
as a marketable skill, Scheme and ML will not.
不过，别误会我们。
Don't get us wrong, though.
你从这门课上学到的真正技能
The real skills you'll get from this course
不是Java特有的。
are not Java-specific.
它们可以传递到任何你可以编程的语言中。
They carry over to any language that you might program in.
这门课最重要的一课
The most important lessons from this course
会在这些语言风潮中幸存下来，
will survive these language fads,
安全、清晰、抽象和直觉
safety, clarity, abstraction, and instinct
为了更好的工程。
for good engineering.
无论如何，一个好的程序员
And in any case, a good programmer
必须是多语言的。
must be multilingual.
编程语言是工具。
Programming languages are tools.
你必须使用正确的工具来做这项工作。
You have to use the right tool for the job.
如果你是一个实践程序员，
If you're a practicing programmer,
你一定要学其他程序
you'll certainly have to pick up other programming
未来的语言。
languages in the future.
所以现在就开始学习第二个吧。
So get started now by learning a second one.
现在由于它的普遍性，Java
Now as a result of its ubiquity, Java
有很多有趣和有用的库，
has a wide array of interesting and useful libraries,
都在巨大的内置图书馆里
both in its enormous built-in library
以及网上的其他图书馆。
and also other libraries out on the net.
它有优秀的免费开发工具，
And it has excellent free tools for development,
像Eclipse，我们将使用它。
like Eclipse, which we'll be using.
即使是Python本身也有一个巨大的库，
Even Python, which has an enormous library itself,
在丰富的生态系统方面仍然落后于Java。
is still behind Java in the richness of its ecosystem.
现在有一些理由后悔使用Java。
Now there's some reasons to regret using Java.
它非常冗长，这使得我们的例子写得更长
It's very wordy, which makes our examples longer to write
更难阅读。
and harder to read.
它像语言一样大。
It's large as a language.
它有许多特点。
It has many features.
内部矛盾。
It's internally inconsistent.
例如，我们已经
For example, the final keyword that we've already
谈论实际上意味着不同的事情
talked about actually means different things
在不同的背景下。
in different contexts.
静态关键字，我们还没说太多，
And the static keyword, which we haven't said much about yet,
与静态检查无关。
has nothing to do with static checking.
Java被旧语言的包袱压得喘不过气来，
Java is weighted with the baggage of older languages,
像C和C++一样。
like C and C++.
所以原始类型和switch语句
So the primitive types and the switch statement
都是很好的例子。
are good examples of that.
它没有像Python那样的解释器，我们可以简单地
And it has no interpreter like Python's, where we can simply
输入一点代码，看看它们是怎么做的。
type in little bits of code and see what they do.
但总的来说，Java是一种合理的语言选择
But on the whole, Java is a reasonable choice of language
现在要学习如何编写安全的代码，
right now to learn how to write code that is safe from bugs,
更容易理解，随时准备改变。
easier to understand, and ready for change.
这将是我们的目标。
And that's going to be our goal.